SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer, with 9+ years of experience on the software industry, go-getter, and over achiever. Have worked in apps used by big companies NYPA, KOHLS, McDonalds, Nike. Experience in different fields like Workforce, Advertising, eCommerce, Communication Systems, Mobile Marketing. Experienced team leader. Very keen on software design patterns, service oriented apps, message-based architectures, distributed apps, multi-server, and multi-tenant environments. Experience on high-demand and high-reliability apps. Software minimalist, dislike ORMs and over engineering.

EDUCATION

- BS in Computer Science, Havana University, Cuba. (2002-2007)
- Artificial Intelligence. Stanford University (2012) (Online course)

SKILLS

Languages: C#, Python, VB.net, PHP, Javascript, Html5, CSS3

Frameworks: WFC Aspnet.MVC, Aspnet, NServiceBus, Razor, jquery, backbone, Castle.Windsor, Spring.Net,

Automapper, Nuget, GoogleAppEngine

Databases: SQLServer, MongoDB, RavenDB, Memcached, MySql, GoogleDataStore, PostgreSQL

Concepts: OOP, NoSQL, SOA, REST, TDD, DesignPatterns, Continuous Integration

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Kaplan University

2014

Education. Worked with Universities around the country. Integrated with external Student systems and Learning Management Systems. Cloud architecture, small and fast paced team. Releases every 15 days, feature-oriented development.

• KAPx. Learning Platform for online courses. Integration with learning management systems, and other systems like Respondus and eCollege. Cloud hosted on appengine.google.com, it manages a multitenant suite where different universities host courses and process student payments and credits

Python Memcached GoogleAppEngine Git

Manager of Digital Development at ZubiAd

2013 - 2014

Advertising Industry. Worked with clients; Yahoo, MSN, or AOL, Chase, American Airlines, Ford. Controlled the development process for the agency campaigns, including a wide range of applications IOS, Flash ads, Websites. Worked hand to hand with vendors and clients. Streamlined the in-house development, implementing best practices. Continuous Integration, git branching strategies, prepared LAMP server environments for development, QA and Production.

• Zubiad. Design and implementation of the company website, superb web experience, responsive on tablet, desktop, mobile.

Workforce. Built a remote branch for the company, Miami based. Backend developer, build REST APIs that interacted with Workforce Platforms (Kronos, Infor), also extensively worked with Communication platforms such us Twilio, Voxeo.

- Orbit. Communications platform, high performance; able to distribute 100 SMS per second and able to
 handle as many incoming responses. Main architect of this system from scratch, built it into a core value
 for the company.
- Shiftex. Shift Manager for employers. Event based architecture. It's currently handing out more than 3000 work shifts a day to potential employees.
- Alerts. Emergency system for the New York and New Jersey Port Authority. Used for high reliability and fast response alert broadcast.
- LSS. Employee Address Book for Lutheran Social Services of Michigan. Manages an average of around 2000 employees' daily updates.

C# AspNetMVC NServiceBus WCF REST SQLServer RavenDb Memcached Razor CastleWindsor Automapper Nuget SVN

Software Developer at Peers Foster Kristiansen

2010

Finances. Backend developer mainly focused on the company finance systems.

- Investor Banking System. Reporting Platform and CRUD website for internal operations. This system never made it into Production.
- BoardSuite. Paperwork automation. IRS filing, employee address book.

C# AspNetMVC PostgreSQL EntityFramework SVN

Team Leader and Software Developer at Vallocy

2009-2006

Consulting. Team Leader at Vallocy, Cuba. In charge of the creation and management of an offshore developing team. Managed all operations, support, business architect, software development and QA.

- QMS. Document Management System, ISO process automation, Word and PDF document manipulation. This system was designed to substitute paperwork in companies that were ISO2001 certified.
- Code Assistant. Automatic code generation. Parser and Lexer syntax for a subset of instructions for VB and Xml.

VB.Net Winforms WPF SQLCompact SQLServer antlr.org ISO2001

Junior Software Developer at Cimex Corporation

2008 - 2005

Ecommerce. Virtual Shop for Cuban retailer. This nationwide site produces revenue of \$30K+ monthly. 3-Tier application, extensive usage of the Factory pattern. Designed to be themed differently, it now host different stores all across Cuba. This project is the perfect mockup of an ecommerce suite.

■ CarlosTercero. Online virtual shop for the biggest Cuban retailer, selling products nationwide. *C# AspNet SQLServer SVN*